What's it to you?
跟你有什么关系
Mind your own business.
你管得着吗
I can't be bothered to stoop to your level.
懒得跟你一般见识
[I had Zhao Yun call you both.]
是我让赵云约的你们
And you are?
你是
Let me introduce myself,
自我介绍下
you can call me Mr. Wu,
我姓吴
and I'm the coach of the Hengyuan team.
是恒远队的教练
Coach Wu Xuan?
吴玄教练
So, why did you call us?
那你找我们是
A tryout for the Hengyuan team.
恒远队的试训名额
Interested?
有兴趣吗
Are you saying we can
你是说我们能参加
try out for Hengyuan?
恒远队的试训
Not both of you.
不是你们
There's only one spot.
名额只有一个
I'm looking for the best player.
我只需要最强的球员
I'll be closely watching
接下来的比赛
the upcoming games.
我会好好关注
I look forward
期待你们
to seeing your performance on the court.
在球场上的表现
Jinghui,
灰哥
what's wrong?
你咋了
Nothing.
没咋
Come on, let's get to class.
走 走 上课去 上课去
All right.
好
[The strength of Chinese culture]
中华文化的力量
[is epitomized]
集中体现为
[by the vigor of the national spirit.]
民族精神的力量
[What is the core]
那民族精神的核心
[of national spirit?]
是什么
[We learned this before.]
我们之前讲过这个问题
Lan Jinghui.
兰靖灰
Answer this question.
你来回答下这个问题
National spirit?
民族精神
Sit down.
坐下吧
Pay attention and stop daydreaming.
好好听课 不要走神
The core of national spirit,
民族精神的核心
as we discussed before,
我们之前讲过
is patriotism.
是爱国主义
[Patriotism is not abstract]
爱国主义不是抽象的
[but concrete,]
而是具体的
[having different meanings]
在不同时期
[at different times.]
会有不同的具体内涵
[In contemporary China,]
在当下中国
[loving the country and loving socialism]
爱祖国与爱社会主义
[are essentially the same.]
本质是一致的
About
那个
our school basketball team...
我们学校篮球队
Basketball team?
什么篮球队啊
Look at the time!
你看看表几点了
Where have you been?
干嘛去了
Why are you back so late?
怎么回来那么晚
You spend all day not studying
一天到晚的不好好学习
and doing useless things.
净整些没用的
What did you want to tell me?
你刚才想跟我说什么
Nothing.
没什么
[Do you know]
你知道这次机会
[what this opportunity means for you?]
对你来说意味着什么吗
It means one foot
意味着一只脚
is already in the door
已经踏入了
of the Hengyuan team.
恒远队的大门
Becoming a member of the national team
将来进入国家队
in the future is no longer just a dream.
也不再是梦想
[Becoming a member of the national team]
进入国家队
Hey!
哎
Jinghui?
灰哥
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
Today's the basketball final,
今天不是篮球决赛吗
I came to warm up.
我过来热热身
You...
你
don't seem right.
不太对啊
Let's go.
走吧
Grab my bag for me.
你帮我拿着包
Hurry up.
快点
Just this time.
破例一次啊
Hey, you...
我说你
[Morning]
来啦
Stop talking and start practicing.
别废话 赶紧练
You all came so early?
你们都来这么早啊
I thought I was early enough.
我以为我够早的
Yeah.
对啊
Let's start training.
练吧
Extraordinary Class 8!
八班 八班 非同一般
Impressive Class 5!
五班 五班 气宇非凡
Class 8, Class 8, every shot counts,
八班 八班 球球必进
every point scored!
分分必得
Class 5, Class 5, sweeping Class 8,
五班 五班 横扫八班
absolutely outstanding!
决不一般
Go Class 8!
八班加油
Go Class 5!
五班加油
- Go Class 8! - Go Class 5!
八班加油 五班加油
Lan Jinghui, go!
兰靖灰 加油
Lan...
兰
What are you doing?
干什么呀
Who are you working for?
哪单位的呀你们是
What's this for?
你要干吗啊
I... I'm here to cheer for my son.
我 我来给我儿子加油
It's fine to cheer,
加油不要紧
but don't bring people from outside
不要把社会上人
into the school, okay?
带到学校好不好
Make them leave immediately.
让他们马上出去
But I... I...
不是 我 我
Everyone out! Leave!
全都出去 撤
Why are you getting so upset?
怎么还急了呢
You all leave.
撤撤撤
Get out.
撤了啊
Why are you still here?
你回来干吗
I can't leave,
不是 我不能走啊
I have to cheer for my son.
我得给我儿子加油啊
I'm begging you,
我求求你了行不行
can you make things easier for me?
能不能让我省点心
Just standing here, you're already
你现在站在这儿
disrupting the school's order,
就已经影响学校秩序了
you know?
好吧
Please leave.
出去
I promise,
保证 保证
I won't disturb the order.
不扰乱秩序啊
Lan Shangjin,
兰尚晋
you're so annoying.
你这个人怎么那么讨厌呢
Ms. Fang,
方老师
who would have thought our
没想到决赛
two classes would meet in the finals?
是咱们两个班遇上了
We shouldn't let the game
我觉得比赛嘛
hurt any feelings of the students.
别让同学之间伤了和气
I'll tell my students
我会嘱咐我们班学生的
to take it easy.
让他们悠着点
The score difference won't be too big.
比分差距不会太大
I don't care about winning or losing.
我不关心输赢
I only care if my students
我只担心我们班同学
enjoy the game.
打得不开心
Winning first place
拿个第一
is just a bonus.
也只是顺便的事
All right, I'm heading back.
行 回去了
They don't look strong.
看起来长相好像也不太强
Are you sure?
确定是吗
I think so.
是吧
How about it?
怎么样
I really put in the effort this time.
哥们我这回用心了吧
Go, go!
加油 加油 加油
Come on!
来
We are
我们是
the champions!
冠军
- Go Class 5! - Go Class 8!
五班加油 八班加油
Get ready.
准备
[You spend all day not studying]
不好好学习
[and doing useless things.]
净整些没用的
[There's only one spot.]
名额只有一个
[I'm looking for the best player.]
我只需要最强的球员
Violation.
违例
What's the rush?
着什么急啊 你说
Nervous?
紧张了
Get ready.
准备
Are you kidding?
开什么玩笑
Do you even know how to play?
会不会打球啊
Jinghui, maybe I should take over.
灰哥 要不我来吧
You go ahead, Zhiqiang.
你来吧 强子
Why are you just standing there?
愣着干吗
Continue play!
打呀
Don't you think of yourself as strong?
你不是觉得自己很强吗
Look at you now!
看看你现在这个样子
If you can play, play now.
能打就打
If not, go home!
不能打赶紧回家
Who said I can't play?
谁告诉你我不能打了
Why are you yelling
你冲我嚷那么大声
at me?
干什么
Referee,
裁判
isn't this a technical foul?
这个算不算技术犯规
Get this old man out of here!
把这老头给我赶出去
Who are you calling old man?
说谁老头呢
Let's talk about it later.
回去说
Let's talk later.
有话回去说 回去说
Come on, come on.
回去说 来来来
What was that?
干什么啊
Don't you think what you said
你不觉得你刚才说的话
went a bit too far?
过分啊
Why are you laughing?
笑什么笑
You don't understand, you don't have kids.
不是 你没孩子你不懂
His grandfather used to do the same to me.
他爷爷就是这么教育我的
Saw his stiffness just now?
你看他刚才那状态
It's a psychological tactic, you know?
激将法 明白吗
Jinghui,
灰哥
I know finals are nerve-wracking.
我知道 决赛都紧张
It's okay, keep going, you can do it.
没事 加油 你可以的
Keep it up, Jinghui.
加油啊 灰哥
[These are small mistakes.]
这都是小失误
[Everyone makes mistakes.]
谁都有失误
It's okay. Stay strong,
没事 坚强
keep pushing.
努力
You got it.
明白
You got this, Jinghui.
加油 灰哥
What... wait,
不是 不是
why are you comforting me?
为什么来安慰我
I'm Ash Lan,
我渣渣灰不是吗
Captain of Chenjun school.
我辰郡之光啊
I don't need concern
我不需要你们这些
from you ordinary people.
普通人的关心啊
You can do it.
加油
Come on.
行了
take it seriously.
认真比赛
Okay, game continues.
好 比赛继续
Lan Jinghui, go!
兰靖灰加油
Go! Go!
加油 加油
Come on, let's do it!
来来 走一个 走一个
- Good shot! - Nice!
好球 好棒
Nice one!
漂亮
See? He's back in the game.
看 怎么样 来状态了吧
[Bi Peng]
毕鹏
likes to go right.
他喜欢攻右路
Defend him there.
就在那儿防他
Chao, Zhiqiang,
超 强子
it's up to you.
就交给你们了
No problem.
没问题
Keep the energy up, everyone!
继续鼓鼓劲 同学们
Go Class 8! Go Class 8!
八班加油 八班加油
Go! Go! Go!
加油 加油 加油
Nice shot!
好球
[And the most important thing:]
还有个最重要的
[piss him off,]
激怒他
make him foul. Get him off the court.
让他犯规 逼他下场
[Unsportsmanlike conduct.]
违体犯规
Come on.
来呀
Jinghui!
灰哥
Class 8 requests a substitution.
裁判 八班请求换人
Substitution.
换人
[Two free throws and possession.]
违体犯规 两罚一掷
Go Class 8! Go Class 8!
八班加油 八班加油
Go Class 5!
五班加油
Class 8 will win! Class 8 will win!
八班必胜 八班必胜
Take a break, come on.
休息 休息 来
Let's rest a bit.
休息会儿 休息会儿
Thanks.
谢谢
Guys,
兄弟们
the first quarter
第一节差不多打就这样
went pretty well.
挺好的
Let's stick
接下来我们还是
to the strategy.
按照战术打
Chao, Qiangzi, Yiming,
超 强子 一鸣
you played great.
打得非常好
Got it.
明白
You played well today. Good job.
今天打得不错 辛苦了
Thanks.
谢谢
Looks like we can win this.
看这情况应该能赢啊
I can't stand anymore, Mr. Zhang,
不行 老张 我站不住了
find me a chair.
你给我找把椅子去吧
Maybe you should go out.
要不你先出去吧
One! Two! Three!
一 二 三
Go!
加油
[After that, it's up to you.]
在那之后就交给你们了
Everyone pass me the ball,
到时候大家把球都给我
and I'll shoot
我只要一有机会
whenever I get the chance.
就会投篮
They're in the zone.
状态出来了
Class 8 will win!
八班必胜
Go!
加油
The ball!
球
Ling Dong shoots as soon as he gets it?
凌冬怎么一拿就投球啊
With so many people, can he make it?
这么多人他投得进吗
Because of the trust between teammates,
因为队友之间的信任
he can shoot decisively
所以他可以在任何时间
at any time.
果断出手
Ma Yiming,
马一鸣
the inside-play is yours.
篮下就看你了
No problem,
没问题
I have plenty of tricks.
我办法多着呢
Holding foul.
拉人犯规
Backcourt ball.
后场球
Once I'm double-teamed,
我只要一受到包夹
their defense
对面的防守
will definitely have gaps.
肯定就会有破绽
Leave it to me.
交给我吧
Nice shot!
好球
[At this point, the other team]
这时候对面肯定已经
[is probably in chaos.]
大乱阵脚
[We need to seize this opportunity]
我们要把握好这个机会
[to widen the score gap.]
拉大比分差距
[If we can lead]
只要我们能在
[by fifteen points]
上半场结束时
[by halftime,]
领先对方十五分
we've got this game.
那这场比赛我们赢定了
End of the second quarter.
第二节时间到
Good job, everyone.
辛苦了 辛苦了
Good job.
辛苦了
Have some water.
喝点水
Here, Ling Dong.
来 凌冬
Thanks, Ms. Fang.
谢谢老师
Lan Jinghui.
兰靖灰
Okay,
好
thanks, Ms. Fang.
谢谢老师
Great work.
非常好啊
Keep this up and we'll win.
再这么打下去肯定能赢
Not bad.
不错
I told Ms. Chai
我跟柴老师说
you'd take
你们今儿会
first place.
顺便拿个第一
We must get first place,
是必须拿第一
right?
是不是
Keep it up!
加油 加油 加油
- Absolutely! - Yeah!
必须的 好
We lost our rhythm
上半场
in the first half.
咱们节奏完全乱了
Don't let Class 5 control the pace.
不要被五班带走了节奏
Stay calm
咱们稳住心态 好吧
and play to our strengths.
发挥咱们的优势
In the second half, Bi Peng,
下半场毕鹏你上
you lead.
节奏你来带
[Guys, it was my fault.]
兄弟们 刚是我的问题
[I was too impulsive.]
我太冲动了
[I apologize.]
在这里跟你们道个歉
In the second half,
下半场上场之后
stick to the plan.
就这么打
I don't see any problem.
没有任何问题
If they keep
如果他们还接着
playing like this,
这么打的话
use your strength, okay?
我们就拿身体扛 好吧
- Okay! - Got it.
好 好
Believe it or not,
你信不信
Class 5 is going to win this game.
这场比赛五班赢定了
Great!
好棒 好棒
Toughen up on defense.
防守硬一点
Both inside and outside, play tough,
外面里面防守都硬一点
okay?
好吧
Okay.
好
Who's that mascot?
那个玩偶是谁啊
No idea,
不知道啊
but the dancing is good.
跳得还不错啊
Pretty cute.
挺可爱的
Great!
好
My apprentice!
徒弟
Xiao Xiaohua!
肖小画
Excellent!
好
Let's get on the court!
上场了 上场了
Come on!
来来来
Go, go!
加油 加油
Huddle up!
聚一下
Come on,
来
last few words:
最后说两句
play hard, we'll win this,
打完我们就赢了
our last high school basketball game.
高中最后篮球赛
Give it all!
拼了
- Give it all!
拼了 拼了
Class 5, Class 5, victory!
五班 五班 必胜
Go!
加油
Isn't that a foul?
这不算犯规吗
Ms. Fang.
方老师
Are you okay?
没事吧
Hang in there.
坚持坚持啊
Go!
加油
Nice!
好
[Class 5 is in trouble.]
五班这次危险了
[In the first half,]
上半场他们还可以
[they used tactics]
利用战术
[to surprise the opponent,]
打对方一个措手不及
[but now they're running out of stamina.]
下半场体力跟不上了
[Their biggest enemy]
他们遇到的最大的敌人
[is fatigue.]
就是疲劳
Scored, let's go.
进球了 走了
You okay?
没事吧
Ling Dong! Ling Dong!
凌冬 凌冬
What's wrong?
你怎么了
Are you okay?
你有没有事
Talk to me.
说话
Are you uncomfortable or in pain?
难受 还是疼 还是哪儿
Referee, we need a substitution.
裁判 我们换人
Jia Letian, you're on.
贾乐天 你上
Okay.
好
Just tired?
还是累了
Yeah, tired.
累了
Let's help him up.
来 先给他扶起来
Are you okay?
有没有事
Let's get you up.
我先给你扶起来
Nod if you're okay.
点头
Here,
来
one, two, three.
三 二 一
Make room.
腾个位来
Here, water.
来来来 水
Lan Jinghui, go play.
兰靖灰 你们去打球
Jia Letian, you're in.
贾乐天 你上
Okay.
好
Pass it to me, pass it to me.
给我 给我 给我
- Defense! - Attack!
防守 进攻
They're already shaken.
他们已经被震慑住了
If they
如果再这样
keep losing points,
继续失分的话
the game is in danger.
比赛就危险了
Lan Jinghui is the key
这场比赛的关键
to this game.
就在兰靖灰
What's going on?
怎么回事
Jinghui.
小灰
Class 5!
五班
Must win!
必胜
Go! Go! Go!
加油 加油 加油
Attack! Attack!
进攻 进攻
Defense! Class 8, defense!
防守 八班 防守
Go!
加油
Nice!
漂亮
Awesome!
太棒了
Great shot!
好球
Go! Go! Go!
加油 加油 加油
Attack! Attack!
进攻 进攻 进攻
Single-sided breakthrough,
单边突破
three steps, score.
三步启动 进球
Watch your distance from the hoop
要注意你三步上篮
during your layup.
跟你篮框的距离啊
5, 6, 7, 8.
五六七八
1, 2, 3, 4.
一二三四
2, 2, 3, 4.
二二三四
5, 6, 7, 8.
五六七八
Your moves were correct,
明明动作都是对的
but it just feels weird.
但就是感觉很奇怪
Right?
是吧
I also feel
我也总觉得哪里
something's off.
就不对劲
I have an idea.
我有办法了
What?
什么
Will this really work?
这样真的可以吗
Of course.
那当然了
If played well, it's a secret weapon.
用好了肯定是杀手锏